<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ModMetaData>
  <name>Better Traders Guild</name>
  <author>Sam Hunt</author>
  <packageId>shunter.bettertradersguild</packageId>
  <description>
    [h1]About[/h1]
    In vanilla RimWorld, the Traders Guild are the faction behind orbital trader events - but their world map presence doesn't reflect this. Their orbital settlements can't be visited for trade like other faction bases, only attacked late-game via gravship. Settlement maps are relatively lifeless, despite supposedly hosting a coalition of wealthy merchants.

    This mod brings them in line with other factions:
    • Shuttle caravan trading at their orbital bases
    • Rotating orbital traders to simulate active trade operations
    • Overhauled map generation with inhabited, maintained settlements
    • Integrated cargo system linking trade stock to physical items

    [h1]Features[/h1]
    [b]Peaceful Trading[/b]
    • Visit Traders Guild orbital bases via shuttle when relations are Neutral or better
    • Settlements cycle through orbital trader types on a configurable schedule
    • Preview which trader is docked before traveling
    • World map shows the currently docked trader type

    [b]Custom Settlements[/b]
    • Overhauled room types (Control Center, Crew Quarters, Cargo Hold, Commander's Lounge, Medbay, and more)
    • Lived-in aesthetics befitting wealthy merchants
    • Physical cargo spawns from trade inventory - steal it and it's gone from their stock

    [h1]Compatibility[/h1]
    • Safe to add to existing saves
    • Safe to remove, just don't be in the cargo vault or have shuttle caravans in the orbit world layer when you do.
    • Fully compatible with any mods adding custom orbital trader types

    [h1]FAQ[/h1]
    [b]Q: Do I need the Odyssey DLC?[/b]
    A: Yes. This mod enhances Odyssey's Traders Guild faction.

    [b]Q: Do I still need a signal jammer to attack them?[/b]
    A: Yes.

    [b]Q: Does this make the game easier?[/b]
    A: It adds more trading opportunities. Settlements have better loot but are also better defended.

    [b]Q: Trader stock rotation/map generation/cargo vault/defender strength is imbalanced!!1[/b]
    A: All configurable in mod settings.

    [b]Q: Why isn't a specific trader type showing up?[/b]
    A: Trader types are selected randomly based on commonality values. Some are rarer than others. Wait for rotations or check other settlements.

    [h1]Links[/h1]
    [url=https://github.com/sam-hunt/BetterTradersGuild]GitHub[/url] - Source code, bug reports, and feature requests</description>
  <supportedVersions>
    <li>1.6</li>
  </supportedVersions>
  <modDependencies>
    <li>
      <packageId>brrainz.harmony</packageId>
      <displayName>Harmony</displayName>
      <steamWorkshopUrl>steam://url/CommunityFilePage/2009463077</steamWorkshopUrl>
      <downloadUrl>https://github.com/pardeike/HarmonyRimWorld/releases/latest</downloadUrl>
    </li>
    <li>
      <packageId>ludeon.rimworld.odyssey</packageId>
      <displayName>RimWorld - Odyssey</displayName>
    </li>
  </modDependencies>
  <loadAfter>
    <li>brrainz.harmony</li>
    <li>ludeon.rimworld</li>
    <li>ludeon.rimworld.royalty</li>
    <li>ludeon.rimworld.ideology</li>
    <li>ludeon.rimworld.biotech</li>
    <li>ludeon.rimworld.anomaly</li>
    <li>ludeon.rimworld.odyssey</li>
    <!-- Third-party mods we conditionally patch via xml -->
    <!-- Even if that's just confirming defs exist before upgrading
         content in our own prefabs with mod content -->
    <li>VanillaExpanded.VChemfuelE</li>
    <li>VanillaExpanded.VNutrientE</li>
    <li>VanillaExpanded.VFEMedical</li>
    <li>VanillaExpanded.VFESpacer</li>
    <li>vanillaexpanded.gravship</li>
    <li>smallmine.HeavyShuttle</li>
  </loadAfter>
</ModMetaData>
